I want to talk about meditation number
10 okay we have to do 27 before you
start your retreat meditation number 10
it's called earth the foundation and the
inner essence refuge on commitments
keeping the refuge vows which we will
cover but the first one is what I just
said okay really the first refuge now is
make your garden glow by patients and
not by biochar fertilizer okay or maybe
both okay that viewpoint or that
worldview that taking refuge is required
for all further Buddhist practices by
tradition okay you have to take refuge
before you can take Bodhisattva vows
before you can take laymen's vows before
you can take novice vows before you can
take medium nun vows before you can take
full nan vows or four monks vows the
8-valve right
pratyusha they all depend on on refuge
vows if you don't take refuge vows you
can't take the rest okay so in the
scriptures
taking refuge the simple vows is
considered like the earth and then all
the trees all the flowers everything
that grows out of the earth comes from
that and then debunker became makes a
big deal about you know I was I planted
iris balls okay and they grow into in my
house they grow into colors okay a pale
yellow and a pale purple very beautiful
very stunning I'll show you a photo
later I just had to take a photo of them
they're so beautiful
and the dirt where I live is 90% rocks
it's just like iron right mr. Dunn if I
take the rocks out of a few square feet
and the ground jobs like six inches you
know and it's terrible and the ground is
hopeless
it takes about three hours to plant a
rose because to dig a little holes just
to pull out all the rocks is impossible
you know then I plant these bulbs then
the iris grows and this colors come out
and I'm looking at the color sensing how
how did that come out of my rocks you
know how did the plan suck the right
chemicals out of the rocks to make these
colors like it's it's it's like weird
you know there's no yellow or purple in
the dirt it's terrible color it's like
brown black and dirt dust and then
somehow this stupid bulb sucks out only
the yellow some to ground only the
purple and then puts it all into the
flower but only in the flower not in the
plant it's weird
it just seems good to me okay but banca
says refuge is the same okay you take
good refuge you understand
taking refuge then all the other
Buddhist practice
produces beautiful colors got it
like everything your tenta practice you
know deep mystical things deep
meditation you know difficult practices
they all come from refuge refuges that
chemical that makes the yellow flower
okay it's in the earth so it's the
foundation so that's why I put you know
it's the same as fruits I put an apple
tree here in the
and whether the rest of your Buddhist
practice is successful depends on
whether you take refuge well it's the
soil I call it dirt and then V says no
no it's soil cat used to tell me that
don't call it dirt they see Michael
thought you'd do the same thing okay so
it's the foundation okay
refugees a foundation so during that
meditation when you do it you can think
of all your practice your meditation
practice your yoga practice your study
and you can try to tie it into your
refuge you know if your refuge is good
your yoga will be good your meditation
will be good and your study will be good
and your service of other people will be
good and if you're at a distance if
you're in message is not to Tom if the
earth is weak it won't be good I have to
tell you bad news about my poop tree
bird poop tree do you know about my bird
poop tree okay I got to tell you about
the bird poop tree the DCI people know
people ask me why do why do creepy like
white gangster drug lords become rich
okay
why do mafia guys become rich if karma
is correct they shouldn't get rich but
they do some of them so then I said
that's called bird poop and they so
what's bird poop and I said well there's
a tree that comes from China it's called
mulberry and you need it because
silkworms only eat mulberry leaves so to
make silk you need silkworms to make
silkworms you got to have mulberry
leaves that's the only thing they like
to eat they're more picky than me
okay and somebody brought it to Arizona
for many years it was secret
in ancient China if it was a death
penalty if you told someone about
mulberry trees and the first mulberry
seeds were carried out of China in the
Hat of a noblewoman who wanted to share
them and she hid them in her Hut in any
way they grow all over Arizona they grew
in my school when I was a little kid and
we used to climb them and they're nice
because they don't need much water and
the birds like them because they make a
little berry mulberry purple berry so
anyway I always wanted a mulberry tree
but my gardener partner said I don't
like mulberry trees they make mess on
the ground you know then one day I went
out I was working in the garden and and
there was a plant about this high you
know and I'm like I asked my party I
said what is that and she said oh oh she
said oh my god that's a moba she said
did you plant that I said no more I
didn't do anything I don't even know
what it is she said it must be a bird
poop mulberry tree because they eat the
mulberry and they're in a rush like
someone trying to get to meditation
class and they they don't digest this
the berries and they they poop the seats
and then the seeds have nice poop
fertilizer around them and they grow
pretty fast okay so I always bragging
about my good karma that a bird pooped
mulberry tree in my front yard but then
they said I don't want it in the front
yard so you have to move it I'm like
okay so I dug it up while I was digging
it up I I split the taproot which is
going to kill it
she said it can't grow now it will die I
said but can I plant it anywhere in the
backyard okay you can plant but it's
going to die then I plant it and it
it's about three meters high now and but
then the Gophers came and these are
little like rats and they live under the
ground and they eat the roots so now I
don't know so the bad news for my bird
poop tree friends I went out to work on
the tree and I touched it and it was
like there's no foundation you know
that's what your life is like if you
don't take refuge company okay you grab
the tree and it goes it just it just
went like this
then I shake it and their roots are gone
all the roots are gone you know this
animal ate them so I asked her do I have
to pull it out she said she said really
we should point out and I said can I
just try so you have to pray for my
mulberry tree I'm still going it's still
going it's trying to put a lease on what
it means is you need a foundation okay
without without those roots forget it
everything else is fake it looks strong
and when you touch it it goes blue you
know you get a little problem in your
life and your practice collapses you
know because the roots aren't good okay
it's like it was really disappointing
I touched today when and as I pulled it
and went and your practice will be like
that if you don't know about refuge if
you don't take good refuge your practice
will be no foundation okay
and and you will collapse the first time
you have a problem okay anyway okay your
practice will be like that also yoga
stuff like that okay
[Music]